philamuseum.org 2018-08-28

# Philadelphia Museum of Art - Web Policies

**Overview**  
Thank you for visiting the Philadelphia Museum of Art's (the "Museum's") website and reviewing our privacy policy. The Museum does not collect individually identifiable information about visitors to our website (e.g., name, address, e-mail, etc.) unless you choose to provide that information to us. This privacy policy explains what data we collect and how we use it. 

**Disclaimers**  
The Museum is a 501(c)3, nonprofit organization. Information on this website is presented purely for educational and informational purposes. Your use of this website is subject to the provisions of this privacy policy, as well as the terms and conditions set forth in the Copyright Notice.

We cannot guarantee the website will be error-free. However, we will make every reasonable effort to make content accurate, reliable and complete. This includes correcting any errors that are brought to our attention. You may contact us at [website@philamuseum.org](mailto:website@philamuseum.org). 

**Privacy**  
The Museum is committed to safeguarding the privacy and security of all our Web visitors. The Museum collects information throughout this website for several different purposes, which are explained below. 

**Viewing the Website**  
_Information Collected and Stored Automatically_  
When you visit our website, we automatically gather and store the following information about your visit. This information is used to develop statistics that guide us in making improvements and enhancements to the website. The information is stored and used in the aggregate only, and is not used to contact you personally:

• The IP address from which you access our website  
• The date and time you access our website  
• The pages, files, documents and links that you visit  
• The Internet address of the website from which you linked to our website  
• The name of the domain from which you access the Internet  
• The type of browser and operating system used to access our website  
• The type of Plug-in and Plug-in version on the system

Also, when you perform a search within the website, the Museum may record certain information regarding your search and use that information to, among other things, solve technical problems with the website and to calculate overall usage statistics. 

This information is stored for the Museum’s use only. The Museum does not sell, rent, or offer the foregoing information to third parties. 

**Cookies**  
The Museum uses technology known as "cookies" to track usage patterns, traffic trends and user behavior, as well as to record other information from the website. For certain services provided on this website, cookies allow us to save information locally so that you will not have to re-enter it the next time you visit. Many content adjustments and customer service improvements are made based on the data derived from cookies. The information we collect from cookies will not be used to create profiles of users and will only be used in aggregate form. Users should be aware that the museum contracts with third party vendors for services that require the sharing of non-personally identifiable information collected via cookies. 

You may set your browser to refuse cookies. If you so choose, you may still gain access to most of the Museum website, but you may not be able to conduct certain types of transactions (such as shopping) or take advantage of some of the interactive elements offered.

If you would like more information about cookies and the option not to have them used by third-party companies during your visit to the PMA website, you may visit: <http://www.usa.gov/optout-instructions.shtml>. 

In addition to using cookies and related technologies as described above, we also may permit certain third party companies to help us tailor advertising that we think may be of interest to users and to collect and use other data about user activities on our Sites and/or Services (e.g., to allow them to tailor ads on third party services). These companies may deliver ads that might also place cookies and otherwise track user behavior. 

**Sending Us Personal Information**  
If you send us personal information—by submitting an e-mail, completing an online form or survey, requesting materials or information, ordering merchandise or Museum tickets, making a donation or signing up for membership—we will use this information to respond to your inquiry or request. We may also use it to contact you to provide information about other Museum activities, programs, membership and fundraising opportunities, products and special events that may interest you. You may opt-out of having your information used by the Museum for these purposes, or you may update your contact information anytime, by contacting us via the following e-mail or postal mail addresses: 

Philadelphia Museum of Art  
Website  
Box 7646  
Philadelphia, PA 19101-7646  
USA

Moreover, when we send you communications regarding Museum programs and activities, you will always have an immediate opportunity to decline further communications by unsubscribing. 

The names and postal addresses of users who have provided such information to the Philadelphia Museum of Art may be shared with other organizations that may be of interest to you for informational, fundraising, or related purposes. In these cases, we may share your name and address with other reputable organizations, but we will not share your e-mail or phone number with these institutions. In addition, all information we do share with other institutions is provided subject to confidentiality obligations limiting the nature of the use of your information and restricting the further dissemination of your information. If you do not wish to have your name and address shared with other institutions for these purposes, you may opt out at any time by contacting us via the above email or postal mail address. 

**Transactions**  
_Purchasing Tickets/Web Ticketing_  
The Museum provides visitors with the opportunity to purchase tickets, programs, and membership online. When visitors to the Museum website choose to purchase tickets online, they are linked to a website powered by Accesso Passport, allowing us to efficiently automate the selling and allocating of tickets in real-time. Visitors to the Accesso Passport website are covered by the museum’s policy. 

_Museum Store and Online Membership_  
The Museum provides visitors with an opportunity to make online purchases from the Museum retail store as well as purchase a Museum membership. When visitors to the Museum website choose to make an online purchase or to become a member of the Museum, they are linked to a website powered by Mi9. You may browse the PMA's online shop without registering or submitting personally identifiable information. 

When you order a product from the PMA Online Store, the PMA will collect your name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, e-mail address, and credit card information to process your order. This information is subject to the "Sending Us Personal Information" section above. The PMA will retain minimal personal identity information for our records, to facilitate better customer service, keep you up-to-date on your order status and to inform you of future products and promotions. 

If you choose to register at our Online Store, the PMA will request the same personally identifiable information used to process an order (which includes your name, mailing address, phone number, and email address). This information is used to create a more personalized experience for you each time you visit. With registration, you will be able to keep items in a shopping cart for review or purchase at a later date, view a history of your past orders, and experience a faster checkout. If you need to change any of the information that you provided, you can safely update it any time you log in or it can be permanently removed if you contact us via the above email or postal mail address. 

Your personal information may be stored by Mi9. More information on Mi9’s privacy policy can be viewed at <http://mi9retail.com/privacy-policy/>. 

**Support the Museum**  
The Philadelphia Museum of Art also provides visitors with an opportunity to make a contribution to our organization through an online donation page. 

The information that you supply during any of the above transaction processes is used to fulfill your order and will also be used to track and analyze transaction trends. This information is also subject to the "Sending Us Personal Information" section above. 

The _Planned Giving Calculator_ is hosted by PG Calc and linked to our website to allow you to explore the benefits of charitable giving. Users of the _Planned Giving Calculator_ are subject to PG Calc’s policies and should refer to the [Privacy Statement for PG Calc Web Products](http://www.pgcalc.com/about/privacystatementweb.htm) for further information. 

**Security**  
The online transactions conducted on the Museum website are protected by security features, including encryption, designed to prevent the unauthorized release of your personal financial data. All credit card information will be encrypted using SSL and complies with current PCI standards. We also monitor network traffic in an effort to make the website available to all users and to identify unauthorized attempts to access, upload or change information or otherwise cause damage to our systems. 

While the Museum has endeavored to create a secure and reliable website, please be advised that the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to/from this website over the Internet cannot be guaranteed. Accordingly, the Museum and its employees, agents, officers, directors, legal representatives, predecessors, successors and assigns are not responsible for the security of any information transmitted via the Internet. You assume the sole and complete risk for using this website and must make your own determination as to these matters. 

Unauthorized access is prohibited and punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act. 

**Children's Privacy on the Web**  
The Museum is concerned about protecting children's privacy. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. There are some areas within the Philadelphia Museum of Art website where children could post messages or provide feedback, but children are discouraged from providing personal information. If a visitor known to be a child under the age of 13 sends an e-mail to the Museum, we will only use it to respond to the writer and not to create profiles or otherwise retain the information. 

**Linking**  
The Museum's website may provide links to third-party websites that may offer various products, services, and/or information. You should be aware that your use of these third-party websites may be subject to separate terms and conditions, information collection practices, and other provisions. The Museum does not endorse, nor is it responsible for, any of the products, services, or content offered in any third-party sites. Before using any third-party service, it shall be your sole responsibility to conduct whatever investigation you deem necessary and appropriate. 

**Revisions to Our Web Policies**  
Please note that the Museum may revise its privacy policy at any time. Occasionally, changes in technology, functionality, content we provide, laws and/or Museum policy may require us to revise policies and practices on this page. We encourage you to periodically visit this page to review our most current policy. Your continued use of the site shall constitute your acceptance of any such changes to this policy. 

Questions about this privacy policy can be directed to: 

Philadelphia Museum of Art  
Website  
Box 7646  
Philadelphia, PA 19101-7646  
USA
